[ 
{"question": "With which does the power to extend or restrict the jurisdiction of the High Court rest?", 
"options": ["A. With the Parliament", "B. With the Legislative", "C. With the Council of Minister", "D. With the Rajya Sabha"], "answer": "A. With the Parliament"}
, {"question": "‘Gobar gas’ contains mainly which gas?", 
"options": ["A. Methane", "B. Hydrogen", "C. Oxygen", "D. Silicon"], "answer": "A. Methane"}
, {"question": "Which is the biggest Public Sector undertaking in the country?", 
"options": ["A. Buses", "B. IT Sector", "C. Railways", "D. Banking Sector"], "answer": "C. Railways"}
, {"question": "Which rocks is transformed into marble?", 
"options": ["A. Limestone", "B. Black stone", "C. Red stone", "D. Grenite"], "answer": "A. Limestone"}
, {"question": "Which ‘Englishmen was fellow of Gandhiji in South Africa?", 
"options": ["A. John delton", "B. Washington", "C. Polak", "D. Trumph"], "answer": "C. Polak"}
, {"question": "By which number the quality of gasoline’ sample is determined?", 
"options": ["A. By its octane number", "B. Iodine Value", "C. Cetaine Number", "D. Mass density"], "answer": "A. By its octane number"}
, {"question": "Due to bite of mad dog the disease hydrophobia is caused by which virus?", 
"options": ["A. Rabies virus", "B. Dengue", "C. Cancer", "D. Chinkengunia"], "answer": "A. Rabies virus"}
, {"question": "Who appoints the Chief Election Commissioner of India?", 
"options": ["A. Prime Minister", "B. Deputy Minister", "C. President", "D. Chief Minister"], "answer": "C. President"}
, {"question": "What is the principal reason for the formation of metamorphic rocks?", 
"options": ["A. Extreme pressure and heat", "B. Extreme heat and pressure", "C. Extreme heat", "D. Extreme pressure"], "answer": "B. Extreme heat and pressure"}
, {"question": "Who said “I therefore want freedom immediately, this very night, before dawn if it can be had”?", 
"options": ["A. Mahatma Gandhi", "B. Jawahar Lal Nehru", "C. Ravindra Nath Tagore", "D. Bal Gangadhar Tilak"], "answer": "A. Mahatma Gandhi"}
, {"question": "A temperature at which both the Fahrenheit and the centigrade scales have the same value?", 
"options": ["A. 40°", "B. -40°", "C. 10°", "D. 20°"], "answer": "B. -40°"}
, {"question": "With which is the ‘Tennis court oath’ associated?", 
"options": ["A. French Revolution", "B. Japan Revolution", "C. American Revolution", "D. African Revolution"], "answer": "A. French Revolution"}
, {"question": " Which is the tax that takes away a higher proportion of one’s income as the income rises?", 
"options": ["A. Land tax", "B. Property tax ", "C.  Unprogressively tax", "D. Property tax"], "answer": "D. Property tax"}
, {"question": "Where is the Sargasso sea located?", 
"options": ["A. Pacific Ocean", "B. South Atlantic Ocean", "C. Indian Ocean", "D. North Atlantic Ocean"], "answer": "D. North Atlantic Ocean"}
, {"question": "Who com merited that Cripps Mission was a post-dated cheque on a crashing bank?", 
"options": ["A. Mahatma Gandhi", "B. Jawahar Lal Nehru", "C. Ravindra Nath Tagore", "D. Bal Gangadhar Tilak"], "answer": "A. Mahatma Gandhi"}
, {"question": "Medicine for epilepsy is obtain from which lichen?", 
"options": ["A. Jaika", "B. Ebility", "C. Parmelia", "D. Antidose"], "answer": "C. Parmelia"}
, {"question": "Up to howmuch age can the Members of the Union Public Service Commission function?", 
"options": ["A. 65 years", "B. 98 years", "C. 60 years", "D. 58 years"], "answer": "A. 65 years"}
, {"question": "Which type of glass is used for making glass reinforced plastic?", 
"options": ["A. Fibre glass", "B. Quartz glass", "C. Pyrex glass", "D. Flint glass"], "answer": "B. Quartz glass"}
, {"question": "Which is the greatest known ocean depth (which lies in the Pacific Ocean)?", 
"options": ["A. 13,025 m", "B. 11,033 m", "C. 12.033 m", "D. 15,033 m"], "answer": "B. 11,033 m"}
, {"question": "At which one place did Mahatma Gandhi first start his Satyagraha in India?", 
"options": ["A. Guhawati", "B. Madras", "C. Bhuj", "D. Champaran"], "answer": "D. Champaran"}
]